<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post</title>
      <link>/blog/blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/blog-post/</guid>
      <description>Reticulate  Hi y’all! This is blog post. A post in a blog for SDS348: Computational Biology and Bioinformatics.
Today, we’ll be talking about RETICULATE
Reticulate is a nifty R package that allows R and Python to communicate
R library(reticulate) number &amp;lt;- (67+88)*4  Python number = 2*5/14 print(r.number*number) ## 442.8571428571429 Here, I gave R some arithmatic to complete and saved it as number. I also gave python some arithmatic and saved it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Data Wrangling and Data Exploration Introduction Anemia is prevelent in women globally. I chose three World Health Organization datasets and joined them. One dataset details the prevelence of anemia in pregnant women, one dataset describes the anemia prevelence in non-pregnant women, and the final dataset details the anemia prevalence in women of reproductive age. These datasets detail the anemia prevalence from 1990 to 2016 across all countries.Each original data set has a variable for country, period, and anemia prevalence with 90% confidence interval in a single variable</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Modeling This is the Washington Health Workforce Survey Data, a survey of health practitioners in Washington State. There are 128 variables and roughly 60,000 observations. Each observation is the survey response of a healthcare practitioner.I have only selected the variable in which a majority of the respondants provided responses and there were less than five levels if the variable was categorical. ActiveCredentialOtherState is a binary categorical variable detailing whether a health practitioner has an active credential in another state.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>